bax-shop.co.uk 2019-12-07

# Privacy policy | Bax Music

Bax Music complies with all of the regulations in the GDPR to ensure that your personal data is handled securely. This privacy policy explains why we need your personal data and what we do with it. If you still have questions after reading the privacy policy, don't hesitate to contact us. You can find our contact details at the bottom of this page.

The privacy policy is updated from time to time so we recommend that you check it regularly to ensure you're aware of the latest information. The latest version can be found at this page (https://www.bax-shop.co.uk/privacy-policy).

_This privacy policy was last updated on July 5, 2018._

## Responsible party

Bax Music (“bax-shop.co.uk”), Basepoint Business Centre, Shearway Road, Shearway Business Park, Folkestone, Kent, CT19 4RH, UK, is the party responsible for processing the personal data as described in this privacy policy.

## Personal data

Personal data can be defined as any information that can be used to trace you as an individual. Bax Music processes the following personal data:

  * Personal details: name, gender, date of birth
  * Address details: house number, street name, town/city, postcode, country
  * Contact details: telephone number, email address
  * Payment details: IBAN/account number, account name, credit card number
  * Account details: customer number, user name, password, IP address
  * Identification details: copy of ID
  * Recordings: camera and telephone recordings

Your personal data is processed whenever you contact (or have contacted) Bax Music. We get various information directly from you whenever you visit one of our websites, create an account in our webshop, subscribe to one of our promotions or services, or when you contact our customer service department.

If you're under 16 years of age, you'll need to show your parents this privacy policy and ask their permission before you can share any personal data with us in order to use our products or services.

## Purpose and relevance

### 1\. Processing your order

When you order something at Bax Music, we need your personal data to process and deliver your order. We also need this information in case you want to return a product to us or have it repaired. For these reasons, we need to know your name, your gender, your address details (for delivery and invoicing), your telephone number, your email address and your payment details which includes things like your IBAN/account number, the account name and your credit card number.

In certain cases, we may also need a valid copy of your ID in addition to the personal details mentioned above.

Your personal data is required in order for Bax Music to create a sales agreement for you. We are legally obliged to keep this information for 7 years.

### 2\. Creating a webshop account

Bax Music gives customers the possibility to create a webshop account which involves storing personal information like your name, your address details (for delivery and invoicing), your telephone number, your email address, your customer number and your user name and password.

In order to make your shopping experience as easy as possible, your account details are automatically linked to your orders so that you can easily arrange returns, add products to your wishlist, and subscribe to our newsletters or loyalty program. It's also possible to link your webshop account to your social media accounts on Facebook, Twitter and Google+.

We save your account details to give you easy access and a seamless shopping experience in our webshop.

### 3\. Visiting one of our shops

All of our shops are constantly monitored by video cameras for security purposes. Images are stored for a period of 3 months and can be used in the event of suspected theft or fraud. They also ensure the safety of customers and employees by reducing the chance of threats, or aggressive or violent behaviour.

### 4\. Contact with Customer service department

Our customer service department is there to answer any questions you may have or offer advice on products you may wish to purchase. They can be contacted in various ways including by email, by telephone, through the website or through social media channels like Facebook and Twitter. In order to help you as quickly as possible, we store your contact information and your calls as long as you are a customer with us or you have a webshop account with us.

Your telephone conversation with our customer service team can be recorded for quality and training purposes and we use these to improve our services. In addition, these telephone recordings can be used when investigating suspected theft or fraud and as evidence. Phone recordings are destroyed after a period of 1 year.

### 5\. Providing you with relevant information

_Newsletter and email_

In order to inform you about our special offers and promotions, you can subscribe to our newsletters by providing us with your email address via our webshop or by adjusting the settings on your webshop account. Bax Music only sends emails to you when you have given us permission to do so.

If you are no longer interested in receiving emails from us, you can always unsubscribe by clicking the link provided at the bottom of the email or by the adjusting the newsletter settings in your webshop account.

_Magazine and direct mail_

Once you've ordered from our webshop, you can expect to receive mail from us occasionally. If you've spent more than £100 with us within a year, you'll get the Bax Music Magazine delivered to your home address for free. If you no longer wish to receive mail from Bax Music, you can unsubscribe online via the ‘Unsubscribe from Bax Music mailings’ page. 

_Online advertisements_

Bax Music can provide you with the latest offers and product information during browsing by tailoring the website to your personal interests. We can do this by analysing your surfing behaviour and activities in our webshop with the help of cookies. Exactly how this works can be found in our cookie policy.

_Social media and communities_

If you'd like to share your experiences with our products or services, you can do so on our website or via our social media channels.

You'll find Bax Music on sites like Facebook, Twitter, YouTube, Instagram, Google+ and Trustpilot. Be aware that any information you share with these sites is available to the general public. For this reason, we recommend that you familiarise yourself with these company's privacy policies so that you know exactly what they do with your information and can adjust your settings accordingly.

Bax Music also has its own [blog pages](https://www.bax-shop.co.uk/blog "Bax Music Blog") where you can find interesting information on lots of different topics. You can add comments to any blog post after you've filled in your name and email address. Once you've posted your comment it will appear on the blog page along with your name. Your email address will not be published.

To always give you the opportunity to adjust your permissions regarding the sending of relevant information and to give you access to our communities, this data is retained indefinitely.

### 6\. Signing up for competitions

_Competitions_

Bax Music regularly organises competitions that are announced on the website, via a newsletter or in the magazine. In order to enter, you need to provide your answer along with your name, your address details, your date of birth and your email address. These details form part of the entry requirements so that we can verify your eligibility to enter and so that we can contact you if you're one of the winners.

One year after the competition has ended, all entry information is deleted.

### 7\. Optimal online shopping experience

In order to offer you the best possible online shopping experience, Bax Music needs to use cookies. These are required to store products in your shopping basket or save details in your webshop account, for instance. By allowing us to use additional cookies, we can track your surfing behaviour and activities on our website and use this information to improve your experience. We need your permission to do this, however. For more information on this, please take a look at our cookie policy.

In order to analyse your surfing behaviour and activities, Bax Music uses Google Analytics and your IP address is made anonymous. Bax Music has an agreement in place with Google that dictates that our data results cannot be used for other Google services.

## Retention period

Bax Music does not retain your personal data for longer than is absolutely necessary unless this is required by law. As soon as the relevant retention period has passed, personal data is either destroyed or made anonymous for further analytical or reporting purposes.

In some cases retention periods do not apply. This includes things like your webshop account, contact with our customer services department and subscriptions to newsletters. If, however, you'd like your personal data to be removed from our systems, that is your right. For more information on this, see the paragraph below on invoking your rights.

## Sharing personal data

The personal data you share with Bax Music is only shared with our partners when it is necessary for the services we provide. Our partners include delivery services, suppliers or repair companies, payment partners and IT service providers. Partners who gain access to your personal data via Bax Music may only use that information to provide services on behalf of Bax Music. Bax Music has agreements in place with these partners to ensure that they will treat your personal data as carefully as we do.

In certain situations (suspicion of theft or fraud etc.) we may be legally required to share your personal data with parties like governmental agencies, the police or the judiciary to aid them with their duties or investigations.

Your personal data will not be sold to third parties and cannot be made public without your prior approval.

Bax Music's websites often contain links to other websites and organisations. Bax Music cannot be held responsible for the way these other parties treat your personal data. We recommend reading the privacy policy of each website you use.

## Security

Bax Music has taken appropriate technological and organisational measures to secure your personal data from unauthorised access, distribution or processing as well as unintentional destruction. Your personal data is stored on secure servers. When necessary, sensitive information is encrypted both internally and when shared with authorised external parties. Within Bax Music, only a restricted group of employees have access to your personal data who need it in order to carry out their duties.

## Invoking your rights

The GDPR gives everyone the power to invoke certain rights when it comes to their personal data. This includes the right to see your personal data, the right to request personal data be changed and the right to request that it be deleted. Bax Music has set up an online form that allows you to easily invoke any of these rights. 

Bax Music does not make decisions based on automated processing with regards to matters that may affect you.

If you have a complaint about the way your personal data has been handled, you can always get in touch with the [Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens](http://bax.sh/op/cmBRiS "Autoriteit Persoonsgegevens") (Dutch DPA).

## Contact

If you have any further questions about this privacy policy or your rights, you can always get in touch with us by email [gdpr@bax-shop.co.uk](mailto:gdpr@bax-shop.co.uk) or by sending a letter to:

Bax Music     
f.a.o. GDPR  
Basepoint Business Centre  
Shearway Road  
Shearway Business Park  
Folkestone  
Kent  
CT19 4RH  
UK

If you have any other questions, you can contact our customer service team by email at [customer-service@bax-shop.co.uk](mailto:customer-service@bax-shop.co.uk) or by phone on 020 3695 2176.
